KERRY WOODCOCK

PROFILE

Kerry Woodcock is a professionally trained and accredited coach, providing leadership coaching, relationship coaching, team development coaching, multi-stakeholder engagement facilitation, and participatory video training and facilitation. She has eighteen years of experience as a facilitator of learning and action; working with leaders, partnerships, teams, and multi stakeholder groups to amplify the power of their relationship with self, others, and the world.

Kerry is a visionary leader, who brings a lightness and rigour to her work: Inspiring and energising her clients to tap into what is meaningful and powerful for them; Championing innovation in her clients by empowering them to find connections between diverse phenomena; Developing strategic thinking in her clients by highlighting relevant patterns and issues and opening them up to seeing possibilities before making the best choices; Acknowledging her clients unique talents, expertise, and skills and helping them find ways to arrange all their resources for maximum productivity; and Challenging herself, her team and her clients to excel through aware, intentional development of strengths and skilled behaviours.

QUALIFICATIONS

Accredited Coach (ACC): International Coach Federation, USA; 2009.

Organisational and Relationship Systems Coach (ORSCC): CRR Global, Benicia, USA; 2012

Certified Professional Co-Active Coach (CPCC): Coaches Training Institute, San Rafael, USA; 2007.

Doctorate in Geography & Environmental Management (PhD): University of Northumbria at Newcastle; 2000.

Undergraduate Degree in Environmental Studies (BSc Hons): University of Northumbria at Newcastle, UK; 1993.

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

Organisational and Relationship Systems Coach (ORSC): CRR Global, Benicia, USA; 2009.

Participatory Video Practitioner for Social Change: Insight, Oxford, UK; 2008.

Professional Co-Active Coach: Coaches Training Institute, San Rafael, USA; 2005.

PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS

International Coach Federation (ICF), USA.

Calgary Association of Professional Coaches (CAPC), Canada.

CAREER HISTORY

NOVALDA COACHING AND CONSULTING

2005-PRESENT: CALGARY, CANADA

PRINCIPAL

Provides a range of services including leadership coaching, relationship coaching, team development coaching, multi-stakeholder engagement facilitation, and participatory video training and facilitation. A partial client list includes: Suncor Energy, Vantage Engineering, Calgary Public Library, The City of Calgary, Alberta Funeral Services Association, The Cooperators, Association for Directors of Volunteer Services, Hospice Calgary, Aspen Family Services, Blue Friday, Leukemia and Lymphoma Society of Canada, Shell Outpost, Dare You Keighley Young People Project, and EPCOR Centre for Performing Arts.

TANZANIA FOREST CONSERVATION GROUP

2004-2006: DAR ES SALAAM, TANZANIA

PARTICIPATORY FOREST MANAGEMENT CONSULTANT

Designed, led and disseminated, through a variety of media (report, film, community workshops), a review of TFCG-facilitated Participatory Forest Management in the Eastern Arc and Coastal forests of Tanzania.

UNIVERSITY OF NORTHUMBRIA

1994-2000: NEWCASTLE, UK

DOCTORAL RESEARCHER AND LECTURER

Carried out part-time field research between June 1994 and March 1998, whilst working in a variety of capacities in Tanzania; Wrote thesis full-time combined with lecturing in Geography and Sustainable Development between September 1998 and September 1999, funded by the University of Northumbria at Newcastle; Awarded doctorate in June 2000; and Published academic book based on PhD in 2002.

FARNHAM CASTLE INTERNATIONAL BRIEFING AND CONFERENCE CENTRE

1998 & 2000: FARNHAM, UK

COUNTRY PROFILER FOR TANZANIA

Briefed professionals by profiling Tanzania and facilitating seminars in inter-cultural awareness and the practicalities of living and working in Tanzania.

TANZANIA FOREST CONSERVATION GROUP

1997-1998: DAR ES SALAAM, TANZANIA

TRAINER AND FACILITATOR IN PARTICIPATORY APPROACHES FOR DEVELOPMENT

Planned, organised and led a series of workshops and community-based training in Participatory Learning and Action; Developed facilitation skills of local NGO and Division of Forestry and Beekeeping staff; Facilitated stakeholder self-analysis of roles in forest management; and Monitored and evaluated community-based farm forestry projects in a participatory manner.

1995-1997: DAR ES SALAAM, TANZANIA

PROJECT CO-ORDINATOR

Managed a community-based project, focusing on farm forestry, improved land use management, and environmental education. Developed project plans and work programmes; Transferred management and facilitation skills to key staff members; Facilitated extension activities with farmers; Collaborated with relevant GOs and NGOs; and Facilitated seminars and community-based workshops at a Forest Biodiversity workshop for Tanzania's District Forest Officers.

FRONTIER-TANZANIA

DAR ES SALAAM, TANZANIA 1994-1995

SOCIO-ECONOMIC RESEARCHER

Developed and led research into indigenous knowledge and local forest use by forest-adjacent communities in the East Usambara Mountains, Tanzania; and Produced Technical Report for Tanzanian Forestry and Beekeeping Division and Finnish Forest and Park Services.

KERRY WOODCOCK PAGE 2